She gave them a gift they could never imagine. They gave
the system a fight it would never forget.
Music of the Heart is a drama, music film directed by Wes Craven.
After Roberta Guaspari separates from her husband, she receives encouragement from her mother to
take up a job of a music teacher at the Central Park East School in East Harlem.
Roberta, played by Meryl Streep.
Assunta, played by Cloris Leachman.
Lexi at 5, played by Henry Dinhofer.
Nick at 7, played by Michael Angarano.
Supervisor, played by Robert Ari.
Brian, played by Aidan Quinn.
Music of the Heart is a 1999 American biographical musical drama film directed by Wes
Craven and written by Pamela Gray, based on the 1995 documentary Small Wonders.
A dramatization of the true story of Roberta Guaspari, portrayed by Meryl Streep, who co-founded the Opus 118 Harlem School of Music and fought for music education funding
in New York City public schools, the film also stars Aidan Quinn, Angela Bassett, Gloria Estefan in her film debut, Jane Leeves, Kieran Culkin and Jay O.
It was Craven's sole mainstream cinematic film not in the horror or thriller
genre, and also his only film to receive Oscar nominations.
The film explores themes of violin, music teacher,
biography, based on true story, violinist.
The tone is emotional.